Many interviews asked to get the medal nod off link it lists, I will show you in two ways how to do
this algorithm and in many universities have been asked in final exams, so pay attention for this very
important exam.
I will create for that, I will create get middle A. Method.
It took and through the perimeter, the structure node had pointer and its returning type would be integer,
so it will return and.
OK.
We create struck note, slow and fast, these are the pointers and assign this low, equal to fast,
equal to had.
So this is that linkage list.
We have five elements the middle note it's obvious that it is at Index two, which is the third element
containing 300 and the memory reference to it, or memory address is three thousand twenty four.
We start checking if head does not equal to none.
Then, while fast, we create two pointers.
While Fast does not equal to null and fast, that next does not equal to now, I am referring, it's
very important to check because fast.
We will see that it is going faster than this little by jumping two by two two knots.
OK, so don't worry, we are going to clarify everything in the while loop.
So while the past does not equal to null and fast for referencing to now, next does not equal to null,
then slow.
Slow your forensic into the next and fast go and reference it to do next to element and nuts.
OK.
This is the fast it moves by do and slow moves by one.
This is the algorithm behind this.
This is the trick.
OK, now again fast.
Does not equal to null and fast dot next does not equal to null, then move again, so fast will move
to and slow moves by one.
OK, now, while fast does not equal to null and fast, the next does not equal to null.
This is equal to not because they're the last one is sort of forensic and pointing to the null.
OK, so fast.
Now what the now referencing there now.
So this will be break and broke and this loop will be exited.
And there.
This is this is the condition, and now it will return slow and not date, so we took the data of that
point.
OK.
This is that how we get the middle not off link list.
This is the reference.
This is the algorithm how to get the medal of Link, at least by making two pointers.
The first, the first will be fast and jumping two knots.
And the second will jump by one known and.
Still reaching fast equal to now, the next equal to none, Richard, to end it, we will return that
data after that slow.
Let's move to the second way.
By the way, we have created this in C, and this code would be the same in job.
So this is the code in Java by making do.
Two things by fast and slow to knots and start jumping them.
OK.
Again, get middle of Lingard list in the second, we would create and get middle note the same way.
Struck note stamp equal to hat.
We create the hat and get length.
We have created this method.
Get length.
OK, we have created it in the previous video.
So please go back and search for it as I get method, get length method and see how we have created.
I will not go deeply now and get the length I need from you to understand that get length returns,
the length of the list.
So I stored.
Get length inside a length variable and I created equal to zero and I will start making this for loop.
And equal to zero, I less than length over two.
So it's middle.
I plus plus it will go through all the elements from zero to length over to make them equal time and
pointing to that next return stamp of date.
OK.
Otherwise, it will return minus one.
This is very simple by create the getting that length by using the length gate length method.
And we passed the stamp and then referencing to this and make a stamp that goes through the loop and
returning again.